Guide to the Martin Harwit papers, 1957-1987
Harwit, Martin papers, 1957-1987
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Martin Harwit papers, 1957-1987
14-7-2402
Martin Harwit, 1931-
25 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, pamphlets, notes, clippings, drawings, and manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Office files, reports, research files, and other materials relating to Harwit's work as a professor of astrophysics at Cornell University and his involvement with numerous organizations in his field.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Astrophysicist. Martin Harwit served as professor of astronomy at Cornell University and as co-director of the History and Philosophy of Science and Technology Program. In 1987 he was appointed director of the Smithsonian Institution's National Air and Space Museum. He received a Ph.D. in physics in 1960 from M.I.T. and taught at Cornell since 1962. Harwit's research interests have included observational astronomy, theoretical astrophysics, infrared astronomy, galaxy formation, and the history of astronomy and astrophysics. In the 1960s, he established research groups at the Naval Research Laboratory in Washington, D.C., and at Cornell that built the first rocket-borne telescopes cooled to liquid helium temperatures. In the mid 1970s, he began studying the history of astronomy and space science as it relates to public policy issues.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Office files, reports, research files, and other materials relating to Harwit's work as a professor of astrophysics at Cornell University and his involvement with numerous organizations in his field. Correspondence files (1964-1987) include Cornell Department of Astronomy correspondence, articles, reports, research proposals, and other materials concerning astronomy, rocketry, astrophysics, telescopes, Hadamard transform spectrometry, infrared spectrometry, research projects, undergraduate and graduate education, and organizations with which Harwit was affiliated, including the Center for Radiophysics and Space Research, the American Physical Society, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy, and others. Also, reports, correspondence, proposals, and guidelines pertaining to committees, courses, finances, and activities of the Program in the History and Philosophy of Science and Technology, and other offices with which it was associated, such as the National Science Foundation, the Society for the Humanities, and the Cornell Graduate School and Development Office; correspondence, handouts, and brochures of the Common Learning Program at Cornell; agendas, minutes, and correspondence relating to meetings of the Astrophysics Management Operations Working Group; and correspondence, minutes, reports, a budget, and printed materials concerning the Space and Earth Science Advisory Committee and an agreement between the U.S. and U.S.S.R. regarding outer space exploration. There is also a large quantity of grant proposals, regulations, reports, student notebooks from M.I.T., diaries, papers by Harwit's students, and printed materials dealing with Harwit's research proposals, including files on the National Science Foundation, NASA, Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratories, Kuiper Airborne Observatory Users' Group, the Shuttle Infrared Telescope Facility, and the Kitt Peak National Observatory. In addition, there are photographs, technical drawings, and oversized blueprints of rockets, telescopes, and other scientific instruments. Includes files on the History and Philosophy of Science and Technology Program, 1984-1986.
Also, folders dealing with individual research projects and other topics; files relating to early nuclear cosmology, to talks given at Cornell and elsewhere (with 35 mm slides and overhead transparencies), including talks on subjects including infrared astronomical observations (Jim Houck's 60th birthday), rocket flights, airborne observations and astronomy, Hadamard Transform Optics, "The Universe as Seen by ISO," Paris (1998), Japan (1999), Hayden Planetarium (1999), the Infrared Space Observatory (ISO), Space Infrared Telescope Facility (SIRTF 1998), laboratory astrophysics, "Time in an Inhomogeneous Universe (early 1990s), lunar observations, cosmic discovery, understanding, the military and astronomy; correspondence; and files relating to a multi-disciplinary course, The Course of Science," taught at Cornell in 1985, which led to his book, "In Search of the True University - The Tools, Shaping and Cost of Cosmological Thought," 2014.
ABBREVIATIONS USED
AAS
American Astronomical Society
AFCRL
Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratories
AIAA
American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics
AMOWG
Astrophysics Management Operations Working Group
APS
American Physical Society
AURA
Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy
CIRAS
Cryogenic Infrared Astronomy Satellite
COBE
Cosmic Background Explorer
COSPAR
Committee on Space Research
CRSR
Center for Radiophysics and Space Research
CSA
Committee on Space Astronomy
CSUAC
Cornell-Sydney University Astronomy Center
HPST
History and Philosophy of Science and Technology
IAWG
Infrared Astronomy Working Group
IRAS
Infrared Astronomical Satellite
KAO
Kuiper Airborne Observatory
KPNO
Kitt Peak National Observatory
LDR
Large Deployable Reflector
NASA
National Aeronautics and Space Administration
NSF
National Science Foundation
SAS
Small Astronomy Satellite
SESAC
Space and Earth Science Advisory Committee
SIRTF
Shuttle Infrared Telescope Facility
SUBJECTS:
Names:
Harwit, Martin, 1931-; Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratories (U.S.); American Physical Society.; Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy.; Astrophysics Management Operations Working Group.; Cornell University. Center for Radiophysics and Space Research.; Cornell University. Common Learning Program.; Cornell University. Dept. of Astronomy.; Cornell University. Development Office.; Cornell University. Program in the History and Philosophy of Science and Technology.; Cornell University. Program on Science, Technology and Society.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Students.; Kitt Peak National Observatory.; Kuiper Airborne Observatory Users' Group.; National Science Foundation (U.S.); Shuttle Infrared Telescope Facility.; NASA Advisory Council.; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration.
Subjects:
Astronomy--Research.; Astronomy--Study and teaching.; Rocketry.; Airplanes.; Infrared astronomy.; Astrophysics.; Hadamard transform spectroscopy.; Spectrometer.; Telescopes.; Science and state.; Outer space--Exploration--Soviet Union.; Outer space--Exploration--United States.; Astrophysicists.; College teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Blueprints.; Drawings.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
I. Correspondence
Boxes 1-8, 24
This series, which is typical of Harwit's earlier office files listed below, consists of an alphabetical subject file followed by miscellaneous files relating to his work for various committees or organizations. Like the other chronological sub-series it includes correspondence, articles, reports, research proposals, and other materials.
Records in Series I concern astronomy; advisory committees on which Harwit served; his organization of workshops and symposia; travel; student advising; and a variety of organizations, including the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), the Center for Radiophysics and Space Research (CRSR), the American Physical Society, and many others.
A. 1986-1987; Advisory Committees, 1963-1987
B. 1981-1985 Files of this period include research materials on planetary spectroscopy, especially the Hadamard Transform Spectrometer; the construction of a liquid helium-cooled baloon-borne telescope with William F. Hoffmann; NASA; CRSR; and annual reports of the Cornell Department of Astronomy.
C. 1977-1981 Included are records pertaining to the Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy; annual reports and other items from the Department of Astronomy; and a number of folders dealing with education, particularly in the Cornell University College of Arts and Sciences.
D. 1972-1977 Primarily alphabetical office files.
E. 1969-1972 Included are files on graduate and undergraduate education, including admissions, enrollment, and other academic affairs at Cornell; materials regarding CRSR; and grant information and regulations.
F. 1964-1968 Alphabetical files.
G. 1995-2002 Correspondence by year.
II. Program in the History and Philosophy of Science and Technology
Boxes 8-9
Primarily correspondence, reports, proposals, and guidelines pertaining to the HPST Advisory Committee, Search Committee, courses, colloquia, finance, student fellowships, library collections, and offices with which the program worked closely, including the Graduate School, the Development Office, the National Science Foundation, and the Society for the Humanities.
III. Common Learning Program
Box 9
Correspondence, handouts, and brochures concerning meetings, workshops, and other activites of Cornell's Common Learning Program, which offers undergraduate courses concentrating on social and ethical issues in contemporary society.
IV. Astrophysics Management Operations Working Group
Boxes 9-10
Agendas, minutes, and correspondence relating to meetings of the AMOWG Council, which serves in an advisory capacity to NASA.
V. Space and Earth Science Advisory Committee
Boxes 10-11
Correspondence, minutes, reports, a budget, and printed materials; subjects include SESAC meetings, NASA, an agreement between the U.S. and the U.S.S.R. concerning outer space exploration, "Collected Letters and Testimony: Task Force on Scientific Uses of Space Station," and other topics.
VI. Research Projects
Boxes 11-21, 23-24
Grant proposals, regulations, reports, articles, patents, notebooks, diaries, calendars, and other materials concerning Harwit's research projects on the following topics: time delay studies, Solar Polar Mission, Lear jet aircraft, infrared astronomy, micron spectroscopy, the Hadamard Transform Spectrometer, submillimeter astronomical spectrometry, gravitational studies, telescopes, rockets, cryogenics, and related topics. Organizations represented in this series include the National Science Foundation, NASA, Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratories, Kuiper Airborne Observatory Users' Group, Shuttle Infrared Telescope Facility, and the Kitt Peak National Observatory.
VII. Photographs, Drawings, and Blueprints
Box 21 and mapcases
Included are photographs, technical drawings, and oversized blueprints of rockets, telescopes, and other scientific instruments.
VIII. Publications
Box 21
IX. Unpublished Research
Box 22
X. The Course of Science
Box 25
- I. Correspondence
  - A. 1986-1987; Advisory Committees, 1963-1987
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Institute of Physics (AIP), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - AIP, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AIP History of Physics Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    - Alpach Summer School, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alpach Summer School, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Cornell University Department of Astronomy, annual report, 1986-87 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Cornell University Department of Astronomy, annual report, 1985-86 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Cornell University Center for Radiophysics and Space Research (CRSR), annual report, 1985-86 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Astronomical Society (AAS) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - American Physical Society (APS) Symposium, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - APS (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Astronomy Department (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Astronomy Field (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - B (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - C (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Far Infrared Spectral Line Observations from G.P. Kuiper Airborne Observatory (C-141), 1978-80 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - C-141, 1980-82 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - C-141, 1983-85 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - C-141, 1986-87 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - C-141: Center for Radiophysics and Space Research (CRSR), 1979-84 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - C-141: CRSR, 1984-87 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - C-141: CRSR, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - D (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - E (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - F (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - G (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - H (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Humboldt Foundation (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - I (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - J (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - K (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - L (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - M (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Max Planck Institute for Radioastronomy, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - N (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - National Astronomy and Ionosphere Center (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Opportunities for Space Flight (Box 1, Folder 40-44)
    - Pending Proposals (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Dr. Nancy Boggess, NASA Headquarters, 1974-82 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Dr. Nancy Boggess, NASA Headquarters, 1982-85 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - O-P (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Springer-Verlag Publishers, 1979-85 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Springer-Verlag Publishers, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - Springer-Verlag Publishers, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - T (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Travel vouchers, reimbursements, 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - W-Z, 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - American Physical Society history, 1985-86 (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
    - American Physical Society history, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - History of Physics Newsletter, 1982-85 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Division of History of Physics, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - University of Massachusetts, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Northeast Radio Observatory Corporation, 1981, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Northeast Radio Observatory Corporation, 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Woods Hole Study Center, 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Woods Hole Study Center, 1985-86 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Paper: Gravitational Deflection of Polarized Radiation," in English, German and Czech (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Physics notes (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Articles on physics, 1914-60 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Articles on physics, 1963-73 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Articles on physics, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Articles on physics, 1975-76 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Light bending, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - B. 1981-1985
    - A (Box 2, Folder 31-33)
    - AIP (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - APS (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - B (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - C (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - China (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Colloquia, 1984-85 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - U.S. House of Representatives - Congressional testimony, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - D (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Drexel University conference, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - E (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Erickson flight (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - European Space Agency (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - F (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - G (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - German interviews (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Guggenheim (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - H (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Humboldt (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - I (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - J (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - K (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - L (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - M (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Max Planck Institute (Box 3, Folder 24-26)
    - N (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - National Air and Space Museum (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - O (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - P (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - R (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - S (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
    - Smithsonian (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Switzerland (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - T (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - U (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - V (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - W (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Y (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Z (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Astronomy (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Astronomy Committee on Courses (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Applied Physics (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Field of Astronomy (Box 3, Folder 45-46)
    - Field meeting, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - CRSR (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - CRSR (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - Department of Astronomy Annual Report, 1981-82, 1982-83 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Department of Astronomy Annual Report, 1983-84, 1984-85 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Travel (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
  - C. 1977-1981
    - A (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy (AURA) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - AURA ad hoc Committee on New Generation Telescopes (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - B (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - C (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Cosmic Background Explorer (COBE) Satellite (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - D (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - E (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - F (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Field Committee (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - G (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - H (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Humboldt Foundation (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - I (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - J (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - K (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - L (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - M (Box 4, Folder 29-31)
    - Max Planck Institute (Box 4, Folder 32-34)
    - Max Planck Institute, 1980-81 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - N (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - O (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - P (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Price - Shivanandan (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - R (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
    - S (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - T (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - U (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - V (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - W (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    - Y (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Z (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Department of Astronomy (Box 5, Folder 15-18)
    - Department of Astronomy - Course Committee Meeting, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Martin Harwit medical file (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Arts and Sciences (Box 5, Folder 21-23)
    - Arts and Sciences - general education (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
    - Applied Physics (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Field of Astronomy (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
    - Field of Astronomy - annual field meeting, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - CRSR (Box 5, Folder 30-33)
    - Department of Astronomy annual reports, 1971-74 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Department of Astronomy annual reports, 1974-77 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Department of Astronomy annual reports, 1977-81 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Travel (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Sabbatical year travel, 1976-77 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - D. 1972-1977
    - A (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - B (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - C (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - D (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
    - E (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - F (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - G (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - H (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - I (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - J (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - K (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - L (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Levin (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - M (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
    - N (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - O (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - P (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Pelzmann (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - R (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - S (Box 6, Folder 24-25)
    - Setti, Giancarlo (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Sloane, Neil (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - T (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - U (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - V (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - W (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - X-Z (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - 1976 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - 1976-77 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Astronomy miscellany (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Department of Astronomy, 1976-77 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Department of Astronomy proposal (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Astronomy and Space Sciences Field Meeting, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - CRSR, 1975-76, 1976-77 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - E. 1969-1972
    - A (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - B (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - C (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - D (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - E (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - F (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - G (Box 6, Folder 46-47)
    - H (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - I (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - J (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - K (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Kahn - Arts College Curriculum Review Committee (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Langmaier, Jaroslav (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - M (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - N (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - O (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - P (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
    - Q (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - R (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - R, 1968-70 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - S, 1971-73 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - T (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - U (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - V (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - W (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - X, Y, Z (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Graduate School Miscellaneous Information, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Graduate School Miscellaneous Information, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Graduate School Miscellaneous Information, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Graduate School Miscellaneous Information, 1967-68 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Graduate School Miscellaneous Information, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Field of Physics, 1967-68 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Sabbatical correspondence, 1968-69 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Committee on Space Research (COSPAR) 12th Plenary Meeting, Czechoslovakia, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Admissions: graduate and undergraduate, 1965-68 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Admissions: graduate and undergraduate, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Gordon Messing Committee, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Cornell academic affairs, 1964-68 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Graduate school course and enrollment, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Field of Applied Physics, 1968-73 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Field of Astronomy, 1968-69 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Grant information and regulations, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Grant information and regulations, 1960-69 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Cornell regulations, 1953, 1964-67 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - CRSR Executive Committee, 1964-67 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - CRSR Executive Committee, 1968-69 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Summer seminars in mathematics (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Machinery gifts, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - F. 1964-1968
    - A, 1964-68 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - B, 1963-68 (Box 7, Folder 44-45)
    - D, 1964-68 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - E, 1963-68 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - G, 1963-68 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - F, 1964-68 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - H, 1963-68 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - J, 1964-66 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - K, 1963-68 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - L, 1964-68 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - M, 1963-68 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - N, 1964-68 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - O, 1964-68 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - P, 1963-68 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - R, 1963-68 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - S, 1963-66 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - P, 1967-68 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - T, 1966-68 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - V, 1965-68 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - W, 1963-66 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Z, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence by Year 1995-2002
    - Correspondence, May-June 1995 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, July 1995 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, August 1995 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, September 1995 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, October 1995 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, November-December 1995 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, January 1996 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, February 1996 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, March 1996 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, April 1996 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, May-June 1996 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, July-August 1996 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, September-October 1996 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, November-December 1996 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, January-February 1997 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, March-April 1997 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, May-June 1997 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, July-August-September 1997 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, October-November-December 1997 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, January/March 1998 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, April, May, June 1998 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, July, August, September 1998 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Letters, September-December 1998 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, January-March 1999 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, April-December 1999 (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, January 2000 (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Supporting Materials Involving the Great Observatories, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 40)